# Nick Sologoub

London, UK

email: <a href="mailto:nick.sologoub@outlook.com">nick.sologoub@outlook.com</a>
web: <a href="mailto:https://ncksol.dev">https://ncksol.dev</a>

### Summary

I am an experienced Principal Engineer/Architect with 15 years of expertise in creating complex enterprise level software. My speciality lies in creating well architectured and thorough backend API layer, driven by the power of Azure Cloud, be it an IaaS, PaaS or even FaaS stack. In my previous experience I had a chance to lead a team transforming a legacy on-premises bare-metal product into a cloud PaaS architecture.

My frontend experience is comprehensive since, as a backend architect, you sometimes find yourself having to help out the frontend teams to realise your vision of the product that you've expressed through API. The biggest part of my frontend expertise is in Desktop tech stack (WPF/Win Forms). But, as it happens with any modern product, you eventually get exposure to all aspects of frontend one way or the other. In my previous job I had to deal with Angular, ASP.NET WebForms and some mobile cross-platform through Xamarin.

### **Skills**

Languages: C#, XAML, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TSQL, PowerShell, Python, C/C++, VB.NET, TypeScript

**Backend Stack:** Azure (App Services, Azure Functions, Service Bus, Event Grid, Storage, Azure SQL, Application Insights), Docker, ASP.NET MVC/Web API, .NET Core, WCF, IdentityServer

Frontend Stack: WPF, WinForms, ASP.NET Web Forms, Angular, AJAX, Visual Studio Tools for Office

Databases: Microsoft SQL, Entity Framework, NoSQL

**Tools/Frameworks:** Visual Studio, Microsoft Blend, PRISM, Unity DI, DevExpress WinForms/WPF Suite, JetBrains profilers, Fiddler, NUnit/Moq/xUnit, CefSharp, WinDbg, Selenium, Postman

**CI/CD/VCS:** Azure Devops, Git, Subversion, TeamCity, CruiseControl.NET, NANT, Octopus Deploy, GitHub Enterprise

### Experience

NewDay (UK)

April 2020 - Present

#### Senior Manager, Lead Engineer

I've been hired by NewDay to fill the role of a technical lead in a newly formed team of API developers. After showing my skills and proving my expertise, within six months I've been promoted to a Senior Manager alongside the Tech Lead role. Since then I've been combining these two roles and supporting my team in delivering the best quality code possible.

As a Tech Lead, I work with Solution Architects to come up with system design for new projects we are planning to work on. I work with team's Product Owner and Business Analyst, to understand business requirements and translate them into technical specifications. I help out in keeping team's backlog groomed and healthy, stories written properly and agile ceremonies followed in the way that helps team succeed. I support developers on my team via sharing my expertise, pair

programming and comprehensive pull request reviews. I also like to write code myself when I have time, writing code is still the main reason I do this job. At this position my main tech stack is around C#, Azure Functions, CosmosDB/MS SQL, event-driven services. But I am flexible and can apply my expertise within any stack required.

As an Engineering Manager, I help people on my team grow and advance in their careers. I support them with regular 1-2-1s, performance reviews and general chat whenever they need me. I try to maintain healthy atmosphere in the team and make sure that everyone is having a good time while delivering value to the company.

# Invenias Limited (UK)

#### **April 2012 – December 2019**

#### **Lead Software Engineer**

As a Lead Engineer in the company, I had two teams under my supervision, reporting directly to the Head of Engineering.

The first team was originally assembled 3-4 years ago when I was tasked with the project of digital transformation of the legacy on-premises backend to a modern cloud-based PaaS architecture. Under my supervision the team proceeded with a range of smaller project to achieve the end goal:

- Developing a RESTful API based on ASP.NET (.NET Framework originally, later .NET Core) for both internal utilisation as well as opening certain layers to our clients for consume
- Setting up platform infrastructure on Azure using all the latest DevOps automation tools (Azure Templates, Azure DevOps)
- Refactoring existing codebase to be better suited to a more distributed architecture in the cloud (utilizing messaging services like Azure Event Grid and Service Bus)
- Optimising DB and model layer to save resources/money on running in Azure SQL databases.

The project was a massive success that has established the architecture of Invenias Platform for many years into the future. As an example of immediate benefits of the project, we've moved the release cycle for our flagship desktop product from once every 4-6 months, to once every fortnight.

In my other role, I was leading a team of several developers responsible for the company's flagship desktop product. It is a complex enterprise level application written in WPF with tight integration into Office products. I was helping the team to realise the API layer in accessible and user-friendly UI, coordinate with other frontend teams (web and mobile) to ensure that UI/UX consistency is maintained and wrote a lot of the frontend functionality across all the teams myself.

The confirmation of my extensive and successful contribution to company's success came two years ago when Invenias was acquired (for an undisclosed amount of many dollars) by a much bigger competitor. The buyer recognised that it was easier to buy the company than to build a better product.

### Memos Software (Czech Republic) Senior Software Engineer

**February 2008 – April 2012** 

I was working as an outsourcing software developer on a project for Invenias (see above). This position was the start of my work on this product. Later on, the company realised the value of having me as a full time inhouse engineer and invited to join the company proper.

EffectiveSoft (Belarus)
Senior Web Developer

**August 2007 – October 2007** 

### Itransition (Belarus) Web Developer

#### October 2005 - June 2007

# Education

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics 2003 – 2008 Masters, Computer Science

# Accomplishments

70-511 TS: Windows Applications Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 70-513 TS: Windows Communication Foundation Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 Coursera.org – Machine Learning by Stanford University

### Languages

Russian – native English – proficient Czech – basic French – basic Mandarin – basic